CAIO FIGUEIREDO

ECONOMIST, PHD CANDIDATE AT PENN STATE

CONTACT

+1 814 699 1729

cgf42@psu.edu apoema.asa@gmail.com

359 Toftrees Ave, 203, State College, PA | USA

EDUCATION

2018 - 2024 (Expected completion)

PENN STATE UNIVERSITY

Ph.D. in Economics

State College - PA | United States

2013 - 2015

UNIVERSITY OF BRASÍLIA

Master's in Economics

Brasília - DF | Brazil

2008 - 2012

UNIVERSITY OF SÃO PAULO

Bachelor's in Economics

São Paulo - SP | Brazil

SKILLS

Proficient in programming in

R, Julia, Python, C++

LANGUAGES

English | Fluent

Portuguese | Native

Spanish | Advanced

French | Basic

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Economist with a solid background in economic research, public economics, programming, and data science. Working for the Federal Government of Brazil, I participated in projects that resulted in legislative and economic policy change. As a Ph.D. candidate at Penn State, I used my strong programming skills to develop dynamic structural models and researched the effects of aging demographics on the national economies worldwide.

EXPERIENCE

2014 - Present (currently working remotely)

NATIONAL TREASURY OF BRAZIL

Federal Financial Auditor

Brasília - DF | Brazil

- As part of the Economic Policies Secretariat, I supported the development of a model to predict the expenses of the Brazilian Pension System under different rules. This model influenced the final Pension System Reform enacted in 2019 by the Brazilian Congress.
- I created an economic model based on historical data and current conditions to predict
 the expected daily cash flow of the Brazilian federal government during the next four
 months.

2020 - Present

PENN STATE UNIVERSITY

Research Assistant

State College - PA | United States

Implement and test research models. Using micro data of developing countries, I
created a dynamic structural model in Julia to calculate the probability of children's
enrollment in school given a financial incentive.

2018 - 2020

PENN STATE UNIVERSITY

Teacher Assistant

State College - PA | United States

 Held office hours proctored and graded assignments for the course 'Introduction to Economics.'

2007 - 2008

VEROS IT

Software Developer

Brasília - DF | Brazil

My first job was at 17. I started as a Web Designer but quickly got a position as a
Software Developer, supporting the development of administrative software for the
Brazilian Air Force. This early position ignited my interest in programming, a skill I
nourished for the rest of my life.